

### CONTACT

### 4044 BUENA VISTA DALLAS, TEXAS 75204



+1-214-836-0567



charlesmartinreed



charles-reed-8021ab161



@supalatecharlie



charliecodes dev



charlesmartinreed@icloud.com

# PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

### CompTIA A+

Candidate # COMP001021147395

### **CCNA R&S**

Candidate # CSCO13177598

### CompTIA Security+

Candidate # COMP000357219282

### HARD SKILLS

### **General Computing**

Windows Adminsistration and Management

Microsoft Office 365 (Account Creation, Management, Training)

Database Administration (SQL and NoSQL)

Desktop configuration and repair

OS Imagining and Backups

Server Setup (Apache, Nginx)

### **UI** Design

Adobe Photoshop and Adobe XD Sketch

### HTML/CSS

# Charles Martin Reed

IT Professional with managerial experience, specialising in network configuration and website development/maintenance.

### PROFILE

As a IT professional, I am always learning, either on the job or in my free time. I am currently A+ and CCNA certified and am currently studying for my first AWS certification. I am a ambitious, diligent and perceptive student who is always willing to pass along my knowledge.

As a web developer, I focus on providing a world-class experience in the browser and strive to write modern, minimalist web applications and websites that delight the user.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# WEB DEVELOPER FREELANCE

January 2015 - Present

Like many other programmers, I've been writing code since my youth as a hobbyist; A few years ago, I decided to embark upon a journey to turn my passion into a chance to earn a living while growing as a developer.

- Developed mobile first web pages with a focus on accessibility and usability using Sketch for mockups or by translating wireframes into fully functional websites.
- Designed single page applications using modern, front-end frameworks like React and cutting edge methodologies like Hooks and Suspense.
- Wrote SQL and NoSQL-based queries (Mongo and Postgres, mostly), often using Node.js for building RESTful backends.
- Provided attractive and responsive websites for customers from a design driven process intended to maximize results while respecting the qualities that makes each client unique.

## REMOTE USER SUPPORT SPECIALIST NOOM

June 2019 - December 2019

Much of my recent, corporate work experience comes from serving in some capacity as a technical support agent. I've been able to leverage my considerable experience troubleshooting and installing a wide variety of software on a multitude of operating systems and hardware configurations and shore up my ability to work within as well as manage groups.

 Noom is a startup company working in the fitness/weight-loss industry, so on any given day our support team might be handling issues with user enrollment, troubleshooting technical issues with our servers or Bootstrap

SASS/SCSS

Webpack and Gulp

**JavaScript** 

React & Redux

GraphQL & Apollo

Node.js

Python

Django

Swift

iOS App Development

#### SOFT SKILLS

Analytical

Goal Oriented

Empathic

Open Minded

Diligent

Imaginative

Calm

Team Player

Accountable

Ambitious

### EDUCATION

### MARLBORO COLLEGE

/ | whir worth of a complexid complexid complexid complexid complexid complexity complex

- the iOS/Android app, researching fraudulent transactions or just responding to feedback from users on the Noom program
- We use ZenDesk for ticket management along with some custom software for interfacing with the payment transaction system - Paypal and their Braintree software - and for managing customers.
- We're a small team (there are about 20 of us) so on average, each of us is responsible for responding to around 140 tickets each day while ensuring that our SLA (0-2 hour response on all support tickets received Monday-Friday, 9-5 EST) is met.
- We use Slack to coordinate between fellow support team members as well as with our extended help desk team, located in Japan.

# CLIENT APPLICATION SPECIALIST | ASPIRA

May 2017 - June 2018

As a contract worker with Aspira, I was able to get my first taste of working remotely as well as providing distance troubleshooting for external customers who had purchased turnkey solutions from the company.

- Worked as Tier 2 agent in Aspira's Fishing and Hunting License tech support team, deploying touch-based Windows point-of-sale systems as well as providing Tier 2 Help Desk (phone and email) support providing hardware and software support.
- Responsible for imaging and post-installation configuration for Windows 10 based POS machines, using Windows SCCM, before they were shipped to vendors.
- Received an average of 2 dozen calls per day, with a typical resolution of around 10 minutes when escalated from Tier 1 agent and triaged an average of 10 issues from the ticket queue, each day.
- Handled troubleshooting issues escalated from Tier 1 help desk agents, via Skype or by calling the customer when necessary.
- Maintained Fish and Hunt Department internal documentation on known issues and fixes for hardware and software problems using SharePoint.

# MEDIA DEPARTMENT SUPPORT LEAD NEIMAN MARCUS

April 2012 - December 2016

At Neiman Marcus, I began as a data entry specialist and quickly earned the respect and trust of my department manager which afforded me the opportunity to cut my teeth in tech support and gain valuable experience managing a small team.

- I worked alongside Neiman Marcus' other in-house tech teams to configure and backup local database to mainframe where imaged documents were stored.
- I was responsible for maintenance on department laser printers, including drum replacement and cleaning with a ESD vacuum as well as general troubleshooting.
- I was responsible driver configuration and troubleshooting for the department scanners which were connected to Windows 7-based PCs.
- I created and maintained best practices documentation for digitization and storage of customer records. I was also responsible for training temporary and seasonal help in department tasks.
- I was responsible for ensuring that my department's daily productivity goals were met and for creating reports of the work that was completed by the team at the end of each day using Microsoft Word and Excel. These reports were then forwarded directly to the Director of the Collections department